Guide to the Max A. Lauffer Papers, 1915-2013 UA.90.F99
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Max A. Lauffer Papers
1915-2013
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Lauffer, Max A. (Max Augustus), 1914-
UA.90.F99
29 Linear Feet (26 boxes)
Max A. Lauffer was an influential University of Pittsburgh professor and researcher who contributed greatly to the study of viruses during his career (1944-1986). His work was vital to the eventual discovery of a vaccine for polio, and Lauffer himself was instrumental in bringing Jonas Salk to work at Pitt. This collection documents his personal life and his career, including technical articles, books, lectures, course material, notes, and records from his involvement with many scientific and religious organizations and events. Digital reproductions of portions of the collection are available online.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Arrangement
The collection consists of nine series:
Series I. Correspondence, 1944-2004
Series II. Talks and Lectures, 1938-2013
Series III. Articles, 1934-2011
Series IV. Books, 1943-2000
Series V. Extracurricular Involvements, 1952-2011
Series VI. Course Outlines and Lecture Notes, 1931-1984
Series VII. Notes and Calculations, 1965-1986
Series VIII. Honors and Awards, 1944-2003
Series IX. Personal Material, 1915-2012
Series X. 2017 Addition
Biography
Maximilian Augustus Lauffer was born on September 2, 1914, in Londonderry Township near Middletown, Pennsylvania, to Max and Elsie Lauffer. He had one sister, Eleanor. He attended Iron Mine Run School and graduated from Middletown High School in 1929. Lauffer received a Bachelor of Science degree from Pennsylvania State University in 1933 and a Master of Science in Biochemistry in 1934. He obtained his PhD in Biochemistry from the University of Minnesota in 1937.
In his work at the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research from 1937 to 1944, Lauffer published on the physical characteristics of the Tobacco Mosaic Virus. This was one of the first pictures of a virus ever created, and his work helped to lay the foundation for the cure of viral infections such as polio. Lauffer also studied the influenza virus and his work with its biophysical properties helped pave the way for the creation of flu vaccines. He also played an important role in bringing Jonas Salk to the University of Pittsburgh to study the polio virus. Lauffer's main research interests while at Pitt were "the hydration of viruses and proteins, and the relationship between the physical or chemical structure and the biological properties of biologically active proteins." He believed that his work on entropy-driven processes in biology was the most important work of his career because these processes are involved in so many other biological processes that involve motion.
Throughout his time at the University of Pittsburgh, Lauffer was an Andrew W. Mellon Professor, administrator, and researcher. He founded the Department of Biophysics in 1949 and chaired the department until 1956. When Chancellor Edward Litchfield reorganized the College of Arts and Sciences into three divisions, he appointed Lauffer as the first Dean of the Natural Sciences. Lauffer held this position until he returned to the Biophysics Department in 1963, when he was named the Mellon Professor of Biological Sciences. He was later named the chair of the merged Department of Biophysics and Microbiology. He retired from teaching and research at the university in 1984, being named Emeritus Andrew W. Mellon Professor of Biological Sciences, and continued to work in the office of the Provost for several years afterward.
Lauffer also loved to travel and did some teaching abroad over the years. He taught at the Marine Biological Laboratory in Woods Hole, Massachusetts. Lauffer was also a visiting professor at the University of Bern in Switzerland in 1952 and at the Max Planck Institute for Virus Research in Tubingen, Germany, from 1965 to 1966. He served as a consultant at the University of the Philippines in the fall of 1967.
Lauffer also served as a consultant to the Joint Research and Development Board and to the U.S. Army Biological Warfare Laboratories, and as a member of several National Research Council committees. He was a member of the first National Advisory General Medical Sciences Council of the National Institutes of Health, and a consultant to the Surgeon General of the U.S. from 1963 to 1967.
Lauffer received many awards for his work, including the Eli Lilly and Company Research Award in Biochemistry in 1945, the Pittsburgh Award from the Pittsburgh section of the American Chemical Society in 1958, and the University of Minnesota Outstanding Achievement Award in 1964. In 2006, the Tousimis-Lauffer Distinguished Annual Lecture in Biological Sciences was established in his honor by his former student, Anastasios J. Tousimis.
Lauffer was a member of many scientific organizations during his lifetime. He was a fellow of the New York Academy of Sciences, as well as a member of the American Chemical Society, the Federation of American Scientists, the American Society of Biological Chemists, and the Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine. In addition to serving as a member, Lauffer was a founder and president of the Biophysical Society and editor of the Biophysical Journal, the official publication of the organization. He was also the co-editor of the publication Advances in Virus Research for over thirty years.
In addition to his scientific work, Lauffer was very active in the Presbyterian Church. He served the Presbyterian Church on local, regional, national, and international levels. He was an elder of the Presbyterian Congregation of Middletown, a moderator of the Presbytery of Carlisle in 1992, a member and chairman of the Council on Church and Society from 1963 to 1971, and a delegate to the World Council of Churches' Church and Society Conference in Geneva, Switzerland, in 1966. He served on the boards of the Pittsburgh Theological Seminary and The College of Wooster. He was also active in the community and was a lifelong member of the World Federalist Association (now Citizens for Global Solutions) and was president of the Rotary Club of Middletown.
Lauffer died on August 8, 2012, and is survived by his wife, Erika, and four children: Edward, Susan, Max and John.
Previous Citation
Max A. Lauffer Papers, 1915-2013, UA.90.F99, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of the collection are available online.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection documents the life and work of Max A. Lauffer, a distinguished University of Pittsburgh professor and influential scientist who was crucial to the creation of the polio vaccine, among his many important professional accomplishments. Much of the material concerns his scientific work and his career at Pitt (1944-1986) through personal and professional correspondence, including letters to and from Jonas Salk; copies of many of his talks and lectures concerning various scientific and non-technical topics; articles and books that he wrote and to which he contributed; outlines and notes for his courses and other work; and many of the honors and awards that he received over his lifetime. Lauffer's participation in many professional and scientific organizations is also evident in this collection.
In addition, there are documents concerning Lauffer's personal life, such as his heavy involvement with the Presbyterian Church. The earliest records include personal material such as childhood photographs and examples from his college coursework. The scope of the collection continues after Lauffer's death with documentation of the Tousimis-Lauffer Distinguished Lecture Series, which was named after him and continues in his honor, as well as items used during his memorial service.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Erika Lauffer on March 21, 2014.
Virology; Viruses; Tobacco mosaic virus; Polio vaccine -- Research; Polio vaccine -- Development; University of Pittsburgh; Biophysical Society; United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. Council on Church and Society; United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A; Fort Detrick (Frederick, Md.); Sarah Scaife Foundation; University of Pittsburgh; University of Minnesota; Pennsylvania State University; Salk, Jonas, 1914-1995; Litchfield, Edward H. (Edward Harold); Longenecker, Herbert E. (Herbert Eugune), 1912-2010; American Chemical Society; U.S. Atomic Energy Commission; United States. Army. Chemical Warfare Service.; National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis; United States. Public Health Service; United States. Office of Naval Research.; Lauffer, Max A. (Max Augustus), 1914-; Eli Lilly and Company
- Correspondence, 1944-2004; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series consists of personal and professional correspondence between Max Lauffer and many different people and organizations. The highlight of this series is Lauffer's correspondence with Jonas Salk and others regarding the hiring of Salk at the University of Pittsburgh. There is also correspondence between Lauffer and other university personnel, as well as colleagues, friends, and others in his field. Other correspondence is concerned with Lauffer's work with government organizations and science related groups. Personal correspondence ranges from letters dealing with religion to his writing of books and articles.
  - Jonas Salk, 1945-1960s; 1.
    This subseries contains Lauffer's letters to and from Jonas Salk during the process of hiring him as the head of the animal virology laboratory, as well as his first few years at the University of Pittsburgh. Also included are correspondence from within the hiring committee and letters of recommendation supporting the hiring of Salk. In addition, this series contains some of Salk's research proposals and reports.
    - Jonas Salk, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Max Lauffer to Jonas Salk, May 27, 1947; 1.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, June 2, 1947; 2.
      - Max Lauffer to Jonas Salk, June 4, 1947; 3.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, June 6, 1947; 4.
      - Max Lauffer to Jonas Salk, June 9, 1947; 5.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, June 13, 1947; 6.
      - Max Lauffer to W.S. McEllroy, June 23, 1947; 7.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, June 25, 1947; 8.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, June 25, 1947; 9.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, June 27, 1947; 10.
      - Max Lauffer to Jonas Salk, June 30, 1947; 11.
      - Max Lauffer to W.S. McEllroy and H.E. Longenecker, ca. July 1947; 12.
      - Max Lauffer to W.S. McEllroy and H.E. Longenecker, July 16, 1947; 13.
      - Max Lauffer to Jonas Salk, July 16, 1947; 14.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, July 21, 1947; 15.
      - Jonas Salk to Dorothea Strawn, August 7, 1947; 16.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, August 27, 1947; 17.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, August 28, 1947; 18.
      - Max Lauffer to Jonas Salk, September 2, 1947; 19.
      - Max Lauffer to Jonas Salk, September 12, 1947; 20.
    - Jonas Salk, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Martin Hanig to Max Lauffer, May 23, 1947; 1.
      - Max Lauffer to Martin Hanig, June 23, 1947; 2.
      - Martin Hanig to Max Lauffer, June 25, 1947; 3.
      - Max Lauffer to Martin Hanig, June 27, 1947; 4.
      - Max Lauffer to R.K. Cannan, June 23, 1947; 5.
      - R. Keith Cannan to Max Lauffer, June 30, 1947; 6.
      - Max Lauffer to J.W. Dingle, June 23, 1947; 7.
      - John H. Dingle to Max Lauffer, June 26, 1947; 8.
      - Max Lauffer to Thomas Francis, June 4, 1947; 9.
      - Thomas Francis to Max Lauffer, June 10, 1947; 10.
      - Max Lauffer to Thomas Francis, June 13, 1947; 11.
      - Max Lauffer to Thomas Francis, July 16, 1947; 12.
      - Thomas Francis to Max Lauffer, July 24, 1947; 13.
      - Max Lauffer to W.M. Stanley, June 28, 1947; 14.
      - W.M. Stanley to Max Lauffer, July 1, 1947; 15.
      - Robley C. Williams to W.C. Price, July 11, 1947; 16.
      - Max Lauffer to R.W.G. Wyckoff, June 28, 1947; 17.
      - Secretary of R.W.G. Wyckoff to Max Lauffer, July 3, 1947; 18.
      - R.W.G. Wyckoff to Max Lauffer, July 14, 1947; 19.
    - Jonas Salk, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Max Lauffer to Dr. Thomas Francis, July 16, 1947; 1.
      - Max Lauffer to Joseph S. Baird, July 29, 1947; 2.
      - Max Lauffer to Joseph S. Baird, October 1, 1947; 3.
      - Max Lauffer to Peter Gray, October 2, 1947; 4.
      - Peter Gray to Max Lauffer, October 3, 1947; 5.
      - Herbert E. Longonecker to R.H. Fitzgerald, October 22, 1947; 6.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, October 25, 1947; 7.
      - Jonas Salk to W.S. McEllroy, November 4, 1947; 8.
      - Jonas Salk to Walter H. Striker, December 4, 1947; 9.
      - Jonas Salk to W.S. McEllroy, December 9, 1947; 10.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, December 11, 1947; 11.
      - Jonas Salk to H.M. Weaver, December 21, 1947; 12.
      - Jonas Salk to W.S. McEllroy, H.E. Longenecker, and Max Lauffer, December 24, 1947; 13.
    - Jonas Salk, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, January 6, 1948; 1.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, January 23, 1948; 2.
      - Jonas Salk to W.S. McEllroy, January 27, 1948; 3.
      - Jonas Salk to Margaret Vojtko, March 1, 1948; 4.
      - Wilton H. Robinson to Jonas Salk, March 4, 1948; 5.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, May 5, 1948; 6.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, June 17, 1948; 7.
      - Margaret Vojtko to Jonas Salk, October 20, 1948; 8.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, October 23, 1948; 9.
      - Max Lauffer to Jonas Salk, October 28, 1948; 10.
      - Jonas Salk to R.A. Patton, November 6, 1948; 11.
      - "Influenza Virus, Chameleon Among Microbes" speech introduction, ca. 1947-1948; 12.
    - Jonas Salk, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Jonas Salk to E.P. Stapleton, February 2, 1949; 1.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, February 15, 1949; 2.
      - Max Lauffer to Jonas Salk, February 21, 1949; 3.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, February 25, 1949; 4.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, May 14, 1949; 5.
      - Max Lauffer to Jonas Salk, May 18, 1949; 6.
      - Max Lauffer to Jonas Salk, June 27, 1949; 7.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, July 15, 1949; 8.
    - Jonas Salk, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Max Lauffer to Jonas Salk, May 13, 1950; 1.
      - Max Lauffer to Jonas Salk, June 3, 1950; 2.
      - Jonas Salk to Max Lauffer, September 19, 1950; 3.
      - Max Lauffer to Jonas Salk, December 21, 1950; 4.
    - Jonas Salk, 1947-1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Proposed Program of Studies on Influenza to be Carried Out in the Laboratory of Human and Animal Virus Diseases, 1.
      - Attempts to Propagate the Lansing Strain of Poliomyelitis Virus in Developing Chick Embryos, 2.
      - Purification of Lansing Strain of Poliomyelitis Virus and Related Problems, 3.
      - Publications, 4.
      - Publications by Jonas E. Salk, 5.
    - Jonas Salk Lab, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Jonas Salk & Edward Litchfield, 1940s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Individuals, 1944-1991; 2.
    This subseries contains Lauffer's correspondence to and from individuals other than Jonas Salk. These letters may be of a personal or professional nature and are arranged alphabetically by the subject's last name.
    - Irwin Bendet, 1961, 1962, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Congressmen, 1946-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Stanton C. Crawford, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Warren Gallagher, 1979-1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Hyman H. Gastfriend, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Otto Glasser, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Herbert E. Longenecker, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Herbert E. Longenecker, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Herbert E. Longenecker, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Herbert E. Longenecker, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Herbert E. Longenecker, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Richard H. McCoy, 1956-1957, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - John McMichael, 1963-1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Arun Misra, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - F.F. Nord, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Wesley Posvar, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Harry Prystowsky, Hershey Medical Center, 1974-1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Edward A. Quade, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Melville T. Sahyun, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - W. N. St. Peter, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Ragaa Salaby, 1978-1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Howard K. Schachman, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Howard K. Schachman, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Howard K. Schachman, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Howard K. Schachman, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Hilla Schramm, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Kenneth Smith, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - S. Srinivasan, 1966-1978 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - S. Srinivasan, 1971-1991 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Wendell M. Stanley, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Rudolph H. Weingartner, Provost, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Norman & Katryn Wright, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Chronological Files, 3.
    This subseries contains correspondence files with individuals that Lauffer had organized alphabetically by last name and sorted by year.
    - Correspondence, 1944
      - Correspondence: A, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - Correspondence: B, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - Correspondence: C, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - Correspondence: D, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - Correspondence: E, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - Correspondence: F, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - Correspondence: G, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - Correspondence: H, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - Correspondence: I, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - Correspondence: J, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - Correspondence: K, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - Correspondence: L, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence: M, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence: N, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence: O, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence: P, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence: R, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence: S, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence: T, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence: V, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence: W, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence: Z, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1946
      - Correspondence: A, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence: B, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence: C, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence: D, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence: G, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence: H, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence: J, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence: K, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence: L, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Correspondence: M, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence: N, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Correspondence: O, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Correspondence: P, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Correspondence: R, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence: S, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence: T, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Correspondence: W, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Correspondence: Y, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, 1947
      - Correspondence: A, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Correspondence: B, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Correspondence: C, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Correspondence: D, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Correspondence: E, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Correspondence: F, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Correspondence: G, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Correspondence: H, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Correspondence: I, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Correspondence: J, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Correspondence: K, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Correspondence: L, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Correspondence: M, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Correspondence: N, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - Correspondence: O, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Correspondence: P, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Correspondence: R, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Correspondence: S, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Correspondence: T, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Correspondence: V, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Correspondence: W, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Correspondence: Y, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Correspondence, 1948
      - Correspondence: A, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - Correspondence: B, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - Correspondence: C, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - Correspondence: F, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - Correspondence: G, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - Correspondence: H, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - Correspondence: J, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - Correspondence: K, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      - Correspondence: L, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 60)
      - Correspondence: M, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      - Correspondence: N, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 62)
      - Correspondence: O, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 63)
      - Correspondence: P, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 64)
      - Correspondence: S, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 65)
      - Correspondence: T, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Correspondence, 1949
      - Correspondence: A, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 67)
      - Correspondence: B, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 68)
      - Correspondence: C, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 69)
      - Correspondence: D, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 70)
      - Correspondence: E, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 71)
      - Correspondence: F, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 72)
      - Correspondence: G, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 73)
      - Correspondence: H, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 74)
      - Correspondence: J, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 75)
      - Correspondence: K, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 76)
      - Correspondence: L, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 77)
      - Correspondence: M, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      - Correspondence: N, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 79)
      - Correspondence: O, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 80)
      - Correspondence: P, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 81)
      - Correspondence: R, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 82)
      - Correspondence: S, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 83)
      - Correspondence: T, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 84)
      - Correspondence: W, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Correspondence, 1950
      - Correspondence: A, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 86)
      - Correspondence: B, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 87)
      - Correspondence: C, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 88)
      - Correspondence: D, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 89)
      - Correspondence: E, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 90)
      - Correspondence: F, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 91)
      - Correspondence: G, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 92)
      - Correspondence: K, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 93)
      - Correspondence: L, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 94)
      - Correspondence: M, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 95)
      - Correspondence: N, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence: P, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence: Q, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence: R, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence: S, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence: T, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence: V, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence: W, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1951
      - Correspondence: A, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence: B, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence: C, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence: D, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence: E, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence: F, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence: G, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence: K, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence: L, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence: M, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence: N, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence: P, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Correspondence: R, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence: S, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 22)